NIKOLAS KLEMME

607 Napoleon Ave. New Orleans, LA 70115 Phone: (314) 637-8792 Email: klemme.nikolas@gmail.com Website: nikolasklemme.tech

SUMMARY

Skilled IT professional with over 6 years of real-world experience including Infrastructure Administration, Service Desk Administration, and System Maintenance. Creative, multilingual leader with a skill set designed to thrive in an enterprise level system. Communicates with both management and clients cleanly and effectively. Currently prepared to pass the RHCSA Cert upon reopening of certification centers. Presently seeking System Administration opportunities in the New Orleans area.

EXPERIENCE

Linux System Administrator, Maritz Holdings INC, Fenton, MO

(Sep 2019 – Apr 2020)

- Promoted to a systems administrator role supporting server hosting and infrastructure with a focus on Linux.
- Responsible for installing, integrating, tuning, and troubleshooting on multi-vendor Linux environments.
- Maintained systems operating within VMWare, AWS, and Azure.
- Performed troubleshooting on Tomcat, Apache, Jboss and Nginx in client environments.
- Implemented meticulous Change Control practices in a modern enterprise production environment.
- Participated in cross-function teams that designed, developed, and implemented systems architecture and supporting infrastructure across the environment.
- Drafted and distributed documentation describing systems design & architecture, logic, and operational processes.

Infrastructure Administrator (II), Maritz Holdings INC, Fenton, MO (Apr 2017 – Sep 2019)

- Promoted to a level two Infrastructure Administrator role providing advanced technical support with a focus on troubleshooting and resolving escalated issues from other teams.
- Maintained inventory of computer hardware and peripherals as well as performed repairs.
- Managed back end infrastructure for Citrix, VPN, and AD Groups with and for Admin Infrastructure (III).
- Worked various internal projects that called upon both technical knowledge and people skills designed to fix inefficiencies, save money, and promote new technologies within the organization.
- Cultivated Admin Infrastructure culture, technical knowledge, and relations with other teams.

Infrastructure Administrator (I), Maritz Holdings INC, Fenton, MO

(Sep 2015 – Apr 2017)

- Served as part of the in-house service desk, fielding calls and dealing with all forms of technical support for a large and varied user base via phone, chat, and email.
- Resolved a variety of software issues involving Citrix applications, Active Directory account management, webbased interfaces, proprietary software, and Microsoft Windows 7/10.
- Documented all issues encountered and the step-by-step resolution process within the service management suite ServiceNow.
- Contributed to an internal knowledge base providing instruction for future Analysts.

Senior Service Desk Analyst, Intelliteach / Dentons LLP, St. Louis, MO (Feb 2015 – Sep 2015)

- Served as part of a trained, resolute team providing first and second level technical support to the largest law firm in the world, Dentons.
- Helped diagnose and fix hardware, software, and network issues for high profile and VIP Clients.
- Managed phone carrier service and smartphone provisioning.
- Performed duties effectively and with a high level of professionalism.
- Promoted to a managing position as Senior Analyst and helped develop and mentor fellow Analysts in diagnostics, resolution, and concise documentation for both software and hardware faults.

NIKOLAS KLEMME

607 Napoleon Ave. New Orleans, LA 70115 Phone: (314) 637-8792 Email: klemme.nikolas@gmail.com Website: nikolasklemme.tech

Team Lead, Customer Direct St. Louis, MO

(May 2014 – Feb 2015)

- Responsible for leading a specialized team of customer service representatives covering distinct support for the Economist magazine, among others.
- In charge of quality control for other Analysts, both in phone conversation and ticket documentation.
- Worked through back end systems using PuTTY to manage and modify a subscription base on London Servers to ensure on the fly changes were correctly implemented.
- Managed VIP clients and escalations from other Analysts to ensure high quality standards were met.
- Oversaw ticket queues for the entire team and confirmed that follow-ups and additional work were resolved in a timely manner.

EDUCATION

University of Bridgeport, Bridgeport, CT

(Aug 2010 - May 2012)

Undergraduate courses in Computer Science and Engineering

Berufskolleg Wirtschaft & Verwaltung Ahaus, Ahaus, Germany (Aug 2008 – Jun 2009)

Technical College focused on Business and Technology, graduated during study abroad year

CERTIFICATIONS

- Microsoft Office 2013 Master Specialist
- ❖ CompTIA A+
- RHCSA (Pending)
- Security+ (Pending)

SKILLS

Technical: Thorough troubleshooting methodology, RHEL 7/8, Windows 7/8/10, ServiceNow, Apache,

Tomcat, JBoss, Nginx, VMware, AWS, Azure, Microsoft Office / o365 Management, Mobile Device Management, PowerShell, Citrix Administration, Exchange Management, User

Administration, Networking Diagnostics, RSA, MFA/2FA, SharePoint

Soft: Leadership skills exemplified by a variety of roles, Communication skills, Interpersonal and

interdepartmental relationships

Languages: English (Native), German (Full Professional Proficiency)

REFERENCES AVAILABLE UPON REQUEST